playtrade.com 2011-06-02

# Play.com (UK): DVDs, Music CDs, MP3s, Video Games, Books, Electronics & Gadgets - Free Delivery

#### Privacy Policy

We take our commitment to your privacy seriously and treat any information you supply to us with care.

  * Policy statement
  * The data we collect
  * Sharing Data
  * Surveys and user groups
  * Competitions
  * ‘Email a friend’

##### Policy statement

 **In relation to the website** : **www.play.com** (‘ **the Site** ’).

The Site is a Jersey-based website owned by PlayLimited and complies with the Data Protection (Jersey) Law of 2005 relating to the personal information you supply online.

PlayTrade S.à.r.l ('PlayTrade') and PlayMedia S.à.r.l ('PlayMedia'), both at 4-6 Avenue de la Gare L-1610 Luxembourg are its wholly owned subsidiaries.

Any personal information that you provide to PlayLimited, PlayTrade and PlayMedia whilst contracting with these entities is stored and controlled by PlayHoldings Limited, located at 40 the Esplanade Saint Helier Jersey JE 49RJ Channel Islands.

For the purposes of Luxembourg's legislation on Data Protection and particularly the law of August 2nd 2002, PlayHoldings Limited is the Data Controller, whilst PlayTrade and PlayMedia are Data Processors. The information you provide to PlayLimited, PlayTrade and PlayMedia may be shared with other companies controlled by the PlayHoldings group that are either subject to this Privacy Policy or follow practices that offer the same level of protection as those described herein.

 **By using our services, you give us your express consent to process your personal data as described hereafter.**

^ Top

##### The data we collect

The information collected by the aforementioned entities when you register with us at the [www.play.com](http://www.play.com/)website is generally used to communicate with you and improve our services where possible, and specifically, to process payments or enable third parties to carry out technical or commercial supporting functions. These functions may be carried out by us or appointed third parties who are bound by Data Protection covenants and must process the personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the Data Protection Laws of Luxembourg.

In addition to personal data such as name, e-mail address, delivery address, billing address, credit or debit card number and expiry date, we also analyse data about participants in order to provide a safe shopping environment for all users. Examples of the data we may collect and analyse include the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, login, password, computer and connection information such as browser type and version, your operating system and platform, the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from our website (including date and time), cookie number, products you viewed or searched for, your purchase history, personal preferences and any phone number recorded or used to call our customer services number. In using the Site you accept that your personal data may be used for such purposes.

We will not sell, distribute or disclose information about you or your personal usage of the Site without your express consent or unless required or permitted to do so by law. If you subscribe to our mailing lists for new release and other information, we also ask you to answer various general questions about yourself. You will be asked to specify the areas in which you are interested so that we can tailor the information which we send to you to cover the topics and merchandise which we believe you might be interested in. By subscribing to our mailing lists, you accept that your personal data may be used for such purposes.

Please note that we do provide links to other sites, which may not be governed by this Privacy Policy and you should view the respective privacy policies of those sites for further information.

Participants have the right to access their stored data, to rectify them if required and to object to the storage of their data for legitimate purposes. We would like to keep your information up-to-date, you may change any of the basic information we keep about you at any time by e-mailing us at [privacy@play.com](mailto:privacy@play.com).

In addition to the information which you supply to us, information and data may be automatically collected through the use of cookies. Cookies are small text files the Site can use to recognise repeat users and allow us to observe behaviour and compile aggregate data in order to improve the Site for you. For example, cookies will tell us whether you viewed the Site with sound or with text on your last visit. Cookies also allow us to count the number of unique and return visitors to our Site.

You can configure your Internet browser to accept or reject certain cookies or inform you when a cookie is saved.

We do not cross the information recorded in the cookies with the personal information collected at the time of your registration on the Site or with your online activity.

Some of our business partners may themselves use cookies on their own websites. We have no access or control of these cookies, therefore we cannot accept liability for any malfunctioning of your PC or its installed web browser as a result of your access to any of the websites.

We may monitor customer traffic patterns, Site usage and related Site information in order to optimise your use of the Site and we may give aggregated statistics to a reputable third-party, but these statistics will include no information personally identifying you.

We may also use the Information we gather to notify you about important functionality changes and alterations to the Site, or offers of products, services or information that might be of particular interest to you. Your information may also be transferred to another company (based in the European Union or in a country ensuring an adequate level of protection) in the event of sale of our company to a third party. In that event, we will endeavour to ensure that your rights and freedoms in respect of the processing of your personal data are adequately and appropriately protected. By submitting your Information and ticking the requisite boxes on any order form or when subscribing to the services available on our Site, you expressly consent to such use and transfer, to the extent permitted by applicable law. If at any time you wish to stop receiving our newsletter or any other information you may have requested from us or any other company, please email or write to Customer Services at the address given for us above or click the Unsubscribe link at the bottom of any e-mail you receive from us.

^ Top

##### Sharing data

We have business and technical partners whom we share data with to handle orders, process credit and debit card payments and provide a range of services, including for fraud protection purposes. They are bound by Data Protection covenants and must process the personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the Data Protection Laws of Luxembourg.

In case any fraudulent activity is detected on the website, or, without limitation, in connection with the breach of intellectual property rights through the use of the website, we may release personal information in order to comply with any applicable regulation or assert our rights as well as our business partners’.

^ Top

##### Surveys and user groups

We always aim to improve the services we offer. As a result we occasionally canvass our customers using surveys, provided that they have given their prior and express consent. Participation in surveys is voluntary, and you are under no obligation to reply to any survey you might receive from us. Should you choose to do so, we will treat the information you provide with the same high standard of care as all other customer information.

^ Top

##### Competitions

Your participation on our website may mean that we occasionally contact you with the opportunity to enter competitions. Entry to competitions is voluntary, and you are under no obligation to take up an invitation from us to enter. Should you choose to enter a competition, we will treat the information you provide with the same high standard of care as all other customer information, and use the information provided strictly within the entry terms of the competition and this Privacy Policy.

^ Top

##### ‘Email a friend’

We may from time to time operate an ‘Email a friend’ service. This is a referral service, designed to make it easy for customers to recommend our Site and related websites or offers to a friend, and is a two-step process. First, a customer sends us the friend's name and email address, and secondly, we contact the friend, telling them who we are, and inviting them to take advantage of a particular offer, or to visit our website. When we contact your friend, we always advise them of the name and email address of the friend who made the original referral. We will not use your friend’s details for any other purpose.

When a customer wishes to sponsor a friend and provides us with his/her name and e-mail address, we reasonably assume that such customer has obtained his/her friend's prior consent in order for us to process his/her data. Customers supply such information freely and voluntarily, under their sole responsibility.

If any of the information you provide on the form you complete when ordering a product from the website or subscribing to the services changes, please e-mail us at [privacy@play.com](mailto:privacy@play.com).

We may occasionally modify this Privacy Policy, such variations becoming effective immediately upon posting to the Site and by continuing to use the website, you will be deemed to accept any such variations.

 **Should you have any queries regarding the above Privacy Policy, please e-mail us at[privacy@play.com](mailto:privacy@play.com)**.

^ Top
